#### Mikhail Garber

25233 SE 42<sup>nd</sup> Dr., Issaquah, WA 98029 (425) 233-0373 mikhail@garbercentral.com http://www.linkedin.com/in/mikhailgarber

# **OBJECTIVE: Principal / Senior Developer / Technical Project Lead / Software Architect**

# SKILLS:

25+ years of hands-on development experience. 15+ years of Java. 20+ years of Oracle. Object-oriented design and programming. Web Services, Service Oriented Architecture, micro services, REST. Distributed systems, highly available architectures. Database and schema design, administration and programming. Public API design and implementation. Cloud Computing, expert on Amazon Web Services. IAAS and PAAS. Big Data analysis and recommendation systems. Full, agile or traditional software development lifecycle. Building solid teams, mentoring and education of junior developers. Task estimates, project and budget planning, formal leadership and management. Workflow applications and rule engines. Application servers. Search-based application and solutions. Object relational mapping frameworks. XML and data binding. Messaging and async. Monitoring and eventing. Strong cryptography and network security.

## **KEYWORDS:**

Java, Oracle, Spring, Springboot, Hibernate, EJB, MVC, Struts, JMS, JSP, JSTL, JMX, JDBC, PL/SQL, stored procedures, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQL Server, NoSQL, REST APIs, HBase, Phoenix, MongoDB, Hadoop, Spark, Pig, Lucene, Solr, Elasticsearch, Tomcat, Jboss, Jetty, Apache, LXC containers, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, S3, EC2, ELB, RDS, SQS, Windows Azure, Linux, Windows, Ant, Maven, Junit, Jenkins, CI, CircleCI, Ruby, C/C++

#### **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS:**

BS in Mathematics and Computer Science
1992-1994 Lawrence Technological University, Detroit, Michigan
BS in Applied Information Systems
1986-1991 Industrial University, Russia
Sun Certified Architect for J2EE platform
Sun Certified Programmer for Java 2 platform

#### **EXPERIENCE:**

## 2016-present Principal Software Engineer II Concur. Bellevue, WA

Led several initiatives converting large legacy applications to smaller, more manageable services. Integrated disperse distributed workflows. Designed and developed innovative loosely-connected lightweight messaging framework aimed at rapid development of business logic decoupled from messaging substrates. Java, REST, Springboot, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS.

#### Mikhail Garber

25233 SE 42<sup>nd</sup> Dr., Issaquah, WA 98029 (425) 233-0373 mikhail@garbercentral.com http://www.linkedin.com/in/mikhailgarber

**2014-2016** Principal Software Engineer – Social Intelligence Salesforce.com, Seattle, WA As part of Salesforce Chatter teams ("Facebook for business"), worked on discovery, recommendation and delivery of relevant content to users of leading enterprise social network and Salesforce Communities. Used traditional databases and Big Data tools to extract and process variety of signals from user's posts, likes, follows, comments etc. to identify and expose trending topics and other relevant information and provide recommendations. Promoted culture of unit testing and many other improvements of the development process.

**2012-2014 Senior Program Manager** *Microsoft, Redmond, Washington*As part of Microsoft Autopilot, designed, evaluated and analyzed very large scale logging, tracing and monitoring systems in Bing and Windows Azure environments. Identified commonality between disperse systems and teams, facilitated emergence of common vision and strategy. Prepared design and requirement documents, developed and validated product features, managed commitments across multiple teams.

**2011-2012 Senior Software Engineer – Global Payments** *Expedia, Bellevue, Washington* Designed and implemented new features and improvements in Expedia's complex SOA environment including Web Services and various internal frameworks. Coordinated development activities with offshore teams, drove agile development processes and improved product release practices.

**2010-2011 Senior Software Engineer** *F5 Networks, Seattle, Washington* Contributed to multiple components of F5 Enterprise Manager product. Responsible for ondevice storage architecture including database-driven storage and free-form search. Implemented collection and processing of per-device performance management statistics, corresponding UI elements, bug fixes and overall improvements.

**2006-2010 Senior Software Development Engineer** *Amazon.com, Seattle, Washington* Engaged in number of challenging projects working on Amazon-size solutions as part of Amazon Payments, Distributed Database Systems and Amazon Web Services teams. *Was primary developer of three new Amazon Web Services*, including Amazon Relational Database Service (RDS) and Amazon Elastic Beanstalk, from conception to public availability. Migrated core business components of *Amazon retail website* from legacy architecture to modern Java / Spring pluggable workflow stack built on SOA concepts.

# 1991-2010 Multiple Software Engineering, Senior Engineering and Management Positions

Retail, Airspace, Defense, Government, Travel, Warehousing, Logistics and other industries

## **OTHER INFO:**

Published multiple articles in industry magazines, websites and forums. Issued US patent 20120072762. Naturalized US citizen, employment is fully authorized.